[Music]
hi welcome back to the channel this is
another ben and jerry's recipe this is
their thick mint this is a topped flavor
came out four or five months ago
something like that
what is it it's a mint ice cream
with
cookie swirl
mint chocolate balls
mini cookies on the top and chocolate
ganache or chocolatey ganache as ben and
jerry's like to call it so if you want
to see how it's made stick around and
we'll show you
[Music]
so for this recipe we're gonna start
with the cookies and i've gone for a
typical blog
recipe online and it's gone completely
wrong
did this last week i'm doing it again
this week it appears so i've adjusted
the recipe based on a bbc good food
website and that's pretty reliable and
as you can see the cookies have turned
out much better baked at 175 for about
10 to 12 minutes but just adjust it to
suit your oven
once your cookies are baked let them
cool on a wire rack but we need to use
these cookies to make three different
cookie dudes i mean cookie elements
so let's start with the mint cookie
balls
[Music]
so whilst a couple of the cookies are
still just slightly warm
break them up into a small bowl and add
your mint extract and just a little
heavy cream
mix all together and then take
approximately quarter teaspoons of that
mix and semi-shape it and put it on a
plate and pop it in the freezer once
they're frozen take them out
and play with your balls until they're
round then put them back in the freezer
next is the cookies for the top so you
need to take the smallest cookie cutter
you've got or whatever it is that's
about 10 to 12 millimeters in diameter
and cut out the little baby cookies just
press them down gently and then put them
in a small container and put those in
the freezer as well
[Music]
finally we're going to need to prepare a
few cookies for the cookie swirl ben and
jerry's cookie swirl is normally just a
dry powder mixed in in layers and that's
what we're gonna do here for this we're
gonna dry a cookie or two in the fridge
overnight to take your dried cookies out
the fridge and break them up into a
really nice fine cookie dust
[Music]
now we're on to the ice cream base
itself this is a really simple one add
all the ingredients minus the cream and
mint extract to a pan and gently heat to
dissolve the sugars when done remove
from the heat and add the cream and
finally the mint extract in the fridge
it goes for a couple of hours
when it's chilled
churn it as normal and get all your
component parts ready
i'd leave your balls in the freezer
until last minute but that's generally
just some good life advice for the guys
watching out there
[Music]
[Applause]
when the churn is complete start loading
up the tub layer in your cookie swirl
mint cookie balls and remember not to
overfill this tub
put it in the freezer for an hour or so
and when the top is frozen just a little
more place your mini cookies on top and
pour on your chocolate ganache then put
it back in the freezer for a few hours
[Music]
straight out the freezer look at that
super cool i don't know if you can see
it super cool very tasteful tub by my
wife she does an amazing job with these
i know you all agree
so before we dig into this
one thing i want to mention
the chocolate ganache for the top this
time it actually went a bit wrong
now
when i heated up 70 chocolate as a water
ganache is what you normally use
it actually started to turn so it split
so i recovered that ganache using the
warm water technique and i'll continue
that little video up here in the corner
so you can see that it just comes back
to normal but
if you do that and recover the chocolate
what it will do
is
bloom
now whilst it will taste absolutely fine
i mean we had another tub last night so
we know it tastes great but
i would also use a different chocolate
so rather than the 70 use a 50 chocolate
it's not quite as bitter and it's much
more forgiving when you make a chocolate
ganache
now that's been said let's get some
scooped up and put it in a bowl and see
what it turns out
[Music]
so there we go
first thing you have to know if you've
never had this before it's not green
now whilst a lot of people these days
don't like
colored ice creams or artificially
colored ice creams i don't mind it for
me mint ice cream should be green but
it's totally up to you you can see the
cookie layers you can see these cookie
little mint bowls in there you've got
the big chunky chocolate top with the
mini cookies let's just dig in and see
what it tastes like shall we
[Music]
it definitely tastes like mint ice cream
it's a good quality mint extract used in
this
i've used various different ones over
the years
some are better than others so you know
try and use a good quality one
now those little
mint cookie balls
they're great they're like little mint
chocolate truffles in there
the cookie swirl which is the cookie
dust layered throughout that's really
nice you just get a little bit of a
texture change in the ice cream itself
the chocolate on the top
[Music]
that's too bitter
like i said use 50 chocolate a 70
chocolate because there's a fair bit of
bit on top
it's a little bit overpowering for the
ice cream but
that side the whole combination actually
is really really nice
i'm a big mint ice cream fan it's one of
my favorite flavors
if you like mint
you try this one if you don't
probably would avoid this one if i were
you
it's one of ben and jerry's new top
flavors that came out a while ago we're
gonna start looking at the others as
well there's loads of different ones
whiskey business and
loads of other different flavors so
we'll get to those down the line but if
you enjoy a nice mint ice cream with
loads of add-ins give this one a try
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
you